Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Cunliffe's book projects: notes, correspondence, and contracts, 1842-1990; MS0125 Series 5; 8.5 Linear feet (Box 45, Box 33, Box 34, Box 42, Box 35, Box 44, Box 43, Box 30, Box 29, Box 32, Box 31, Box 40, Box 41, Box 38, Box 39, Box 36, Box 37)
  - Bibliographies for The Literature of the United States book chapters, undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes -- Introduction, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 2: Colonial American, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 3: Promises and Problems of Independence, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 4: A Trio of Gents (Irving, Copper, Poe), undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 5: New England's Day, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 6: Melville and Whitman, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 7: More New Englanders, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 8: American Humor and the West (Twain and predecessors), undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 8: American Humor and the West (Twain and predecessors), undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 9: Realism in Prose, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 10: Cosmopolitans, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 12: Coming of Age: Poetry and Fiction, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 13: Southland, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 14: Melting Pot, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition drafts and notes - Chapter 15: American Theater, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - The Literature of the United States, 1986 edition front matter and corrections, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapters 1 and 2: The Colonials and American & Europe, 1950-1952 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 3: Independence: The First Fruits - Irving, Cooper, Poe, 1950-1953 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 4: New England's Day - Emerson, Thoreau, Hawthorne, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 5: More New Englanders, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 6: Whitman and Melville, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 7: Humor, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 8: Lean Years (minor key?) - Emily Dickinson and others, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 9: Realism and Prose, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Literature of the United States book - Chapter 10: Henry James and the Expatriates, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 11: The New Poetry, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 12: Fiction Since Word War I, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 13: Poetry and Criticism since World War II, 1950-1952 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 14: The American Theater, 1950 ca. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- Chapter 1: Introduction, undated (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- Chapter 3: Promises and Problems of Independence, undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 4: A Trio of Gents (Irving, Copper, Poe), undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 5: New England's Day (Emerson, Thoreau, Hawthorne), undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 6: Melville and Whitman, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 7: More New Englanders, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 10: Cosmopolitans -- Henry James and company, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 11: Women's Voices, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 12: Coming of Age - Poetry and Fiction, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 13: Southland, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 15: American literature since 1945, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 15: American literature earlier 20th century, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 15: American literature 20th century, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 15: Established Modernism -- Fiction, Poetry, Criticism, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 15: Post Modernism, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 16: The American Theater, undated (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Chapter 17: America and the Word, undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- correspondence regarding revisions, 1954-1959 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- correspondence regarding revisions, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- correspondence, articles, reviews, 1954-1959 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- correspondence, reviews, 1954-1959 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- edits to chapter on Poe and Cooper, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- memorandum of agreement, correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - The Literature of the United States book -- notes on the 4th edition (including table of contents), undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The Literature of the United States book - Piper & Co. (Germany) edition correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Macmillan Publishers - London, 1988-1990 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Monarchy and Republic book, 1949-1983 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Anarchy and Despotism, 1957-1982 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- British republicanism, 1889-1978 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Early National era, 1822-1983 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Early national era, 1915-1982 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Early National era, 1961-1979 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Foreign criticisms of the U.S., 1842-1986 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- James Madison as Commander-in-Chief, 1960 ca. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Literature and class in 19th century America, 1922-1985 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Mark Twain I, 1875-1974 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Mark Twain II, 1917-1984 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Mark Twain III, 1868-1961 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Mark Twain IV, 1929-1981 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Misgivings regarding Republicanism, 1841-1970 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Napolean, 1953-1987 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Republic vs. Democracy, 1860-1984 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Republic women, 1942-1980 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Republican alternatives, 1889-1979 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Republican religion, 1933-1985 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Rhetoric of Republicanism since 1870, 1882-1982 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Rhetoric of Republicanism to 1870, 1851-1976 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- Rhetoric of Republicanism to 1870, 1851-1976 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- size of Republics, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Monarchy and Republic book -- South and Slavery, 1891-1987 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Monarchy and republic, 1946-1978 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Monarchy and republic, 1963-1977 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Monarchy and republic, 1964-1978 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americans - Introduction, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americans - Chapter 1: The Prevalence of Monarchy, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Monarchy, Republicanism, and the Americans - Chapter 2: The Dethroning of George III, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Monarchy, Republic, and America - Chapter 4: The Two Georges, Washington and Guelph, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "Nation Takes Shape, 1789-1837" -- book and notes, 1969-1976 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Notes for book on Mason Locke Weems interpretation of George Washington, 1961-1962 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Notes for book project - The Separate Republic, 1970-1990 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Notes for Orbis publishing on "American Destiny,", 1985 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Notes for unspecified book - Chapter 3 and 4: Foreign policy, the West, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Notes for unspecified book - Chapter 5: Commerce and industry, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Notes for unspecified book - Chapter 6: Nationalism and sectionalism, undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Notes for unspecified book - Chapter 7: Middle class democracy in early republican America, undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Orbis publisher's book -- correspondence, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 1 (published 1986) -- Colonial America, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 2 -- War of Independence, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 3 -- New Nation (1783-1815), 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 4 -- The American Character (1815-1860), 1974 ca. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 6 -- House Divided, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 7 -- Civil War, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 11 -- Progress and Poverty, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 13 -- The 1920's, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 14 -- Depression Years, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 16 -- Global War, 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 17 -- Day Before Yesterday (1945-1960), 1972 ca. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Orbis publisher's book notes and drafts, Vol. 19 -- The Unquiet Years (1960-1973), 1972-1974 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Orbis publisher's book The American Destiny - bibliographies for volumes 1-20, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Orbis publisher's book The American Destiny - chapter drafts, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Orbis publisher's book The American Destiny - correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Orbis, Grolier publisher correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - A Paradise for Devils? The Argument About America book deal, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Publisher memorandum of agreement for "From Sav-age to Sew-age", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Publishers correspondence - American Heritage and others, 1982-1987 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Requests for reprint permissions regarding Cunliffe's book In Search of America, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Revision of Life of George Washington (1832) by John Marshall with introduction by Cunliffe, 1980-1983 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Revisions for 1986 edition of American Presidents and the Presidency, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - In Search of America: Transatlantic Essays, 1951-1990 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - In Search of America: Transatlantic Essays, 1951-1990 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - In Search of America: Transatlantic Essays, 1951-1990 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - In Search of America: Transatlantic Essays, 1951-1990 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - In Search of America: Transatlantic Essays - and research notes, 1951-1990 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Separate Republic book outline, 1972-1990 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Separate Republic book outline, 1982-1988 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- American military attitudes: correspondence, notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- American military attitudes: notebooks, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 2: Colonial and Revolutionary, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 2: Confused Heritage, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 2: The Peace Movement, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 4: Militia Burlesques, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 4: Militia Volunteers, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 4: Militia Volunteers -- organization, problems, decline, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 4: West Point, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 6: Military Schools, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 8: Colonel Elmer E. Ellsworth, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 8: Irish Militia and Know-Nothing hostility, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 8: Martial Spirit, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 8: The Unpopular Regulars, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 8: The Unpopular Regulars, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 9: Militia and Politics, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 11: Soldiers, Officers, and Politics, undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 11: Women's Voices, undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 12: Background to Civil War -- Southern military traditions, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 12: Epilogue, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Soldiers and Civilians book -- Chapter 12: The Idea of the South, undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Soldiers and civilians, 1953-1989 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Soldiers and Civilians: American Martialism, 1969-1990 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Soldiers and Civilians: American Martialism, 1969-1990 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Sphere Books correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Sphere publishing - book on American Literature since 1900, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Sphere publishing - book on American Literature since 1900, 1985-1986 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Sphere publishing - book on American Literature since 1900; Literary Criticism, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Sphere publishing - book on American Literature since 1900; revisions, 1985-1986 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Sphere publishing - book on American Literature to 1900, 1981-1989 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Sphere publishing - book on American Literature to 1900, 1981-1989 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - The Royal Irish Fusilers, 1793-1950 book - notes, 1947-1950 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - The Royal Irish Fusilers, 1793-1950 book - notes, 1950-1953 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The Separate Republic book - Anglo-America (Richard Grant White, 1821-85), 1978-1990 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - The Separate Republic book - Anglo-America notes, 1978-1990 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - University of California Press - Jefferson Memorial Lectures, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - World of the Roosevelt's book contract, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: America at the Great Exhibition of 1851, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: America's Imaginary Wars, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: American Watersheds, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Backward Glances, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Bibliography of works by Cunliffe, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Birth Pangs, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Crvecoeur Revisited, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: European Anti-Americanism, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: European Images of America, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Frances Trollope, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: George Washington's Generalship, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Index, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Introduction, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: John Marshall's George Washington, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Madison as Commander-in-Chief, 1990 ca. (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Mark Train and His "English" Novels, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Monumental Washington, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: New World, Old World: The Historical Antithesis, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Old World, New World, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Stephen Crane and the American Background of Maggie, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: The Doubled Images of Washington and Lincoln, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: The Presidential Elections of 1789 and 1792, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: The Two Georges: The President and King, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: "They Will All Speak English": Some Cultural Consequences of Independence, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Victorian America and After, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: What was the Matter with Henry Adams, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Willa Cather and Frederick Jackson Turner, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Woodrow Wilson's George Washington, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Drafts and Notes for Transatlantic Essays: Works by Marcus Cunliffe, 1990 ca. (Box 45, Folder 14)
- Research notes and articles, 1823-1988; MS0125 Series 6; 14 Linear feet (Box 46, Box 45, Box 66, Box 65, Box 64, Box 63, Box 69, Box 68, Box 67, Box 58, Box 70, Box 71, Box 72, Box 62, Box 61, Box 60, Box 59, Box 57, Box 55, Box 56, Box 74, Box 73, Box 75, Box 49, Box 50, Box 47, Box 48, Box 53, Box 54, Box 51, Box 52)
  This series consists of research notes (including photocopied portions of books), lecture notes, and articles on various subjects Cunliffe studied. These includes topics such as: George Washington, Abraham Lincoln, Henry James, the American presidency, slavery, property, military, heroism, monarchy, and republicanism. It includes original military ballads and court martial reports from the 1850s.
  - 2nd 1/7 Battalions at Normandy, 1955 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - 19th Century America - notes, 1954-1975 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - 1776 and All That (Jazz) - notes, undated (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Abolitionism and wage slavery, 1943-1979 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Abraham Lincoln - notes, 1862-1987 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Abraham Lincoln - notes, 1862-1987 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Abraham Lincoln - notes, 1960-1972 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Abraham Lincoln imagery, 1908-1987 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Advertisements using Presidential images, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - America and the China concept, 1808-1953 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - America and the great exhibition of 1851, 1951 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - America in 1919, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - America in Decline, 1987-1989 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - America's Imaginary Wars (see also box 97), 1988 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - American art and architecture, 1947-1968 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - American Art, 1959-1963 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - American Catholicism, 19th century, 1893 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - American Exceptionalism - notes, 1954-1977 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - American identity, 1960-1963 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - American literary realism, 1884-1902 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - American Literature - 19th century, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - American Literature - correspondence with publishers, 1975-1983 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - American Literature - since 1945, 1971-1985 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - American literature and society in the 1920's, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - American Poetry, Poetics and poetic movements since 1950, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - American pragmatism, 1922-1977 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - American Presidency - Nixon, 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - American Presidents - notes, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - American prose and literature since 1900, 1952-1954 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - The American Question by W.W. Story and Notes on American Military Attitudes, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - American Zeitgeist: The 1960's and After (photo included), 1979-1980 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Anglo-American conflicts, 1951-1953 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Anglo-American discord -- American criticism of Britain, 1851-1860 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Anglo-American discord -- British criticism of the U.S., 1847 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Anglo-American discord and the problem of slavery, 1835-1970 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Anti-American attitudes, 1953-1986 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Anti-American attitudes, 1953-1986 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Anti-Federalists - arguments and emotions, 1976-1987 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Anti-intellectualism, 1950-1958 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Articles from Foreign Affairs magazine, 1949-1985 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Articles on 19th Century America, 1850-1981 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Articles on 19th Century America, 1867-1985 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Articles on 19th Century America, 1881-1981 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Articles on American literature and architecture, 1951 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Articles on Private Property, 1929-1979 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Articles on Private Property, 1960-1981 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Articles on Private Property, 1960-1985 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Articles on style and syntax, 1983-1986 (Box 48, Folder 8)